<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
    xml:id="Identity-Service-Concepts-e1362">
    <title>Concepts</title>
    <para> The basic function of the authentication service is to
        validate a client's credentials. If a client offers valid
        credentials, Auth returns a token and a service catalog. The
        client can use the service catalog to find endpoints for the
        services it can use. To any of those services, the client can
        show the token as evidence of having been authenticated. </para>
    <!-- .SVG exists but doesn't use the right fonts: .PNG matches the source .VSD 
    at 100% natural size as exported, the .PNG fits HTML but is too large for PDF -->
    <figure xml:id="token-flow">
        <title>A client sends credentials to the Auth service; if they are valid, the Auth service returns a token which can be used
        to identify the client to other services.
        </title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata scale="75" fileref="../figures/auth-keystone-identity-manager.png" format="PNG" align="center"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para> After a client has obtained a token from Auth, it sends the
        token along with its request to a service. The service then
        asks Auth for confirmation that this is a valid token for this
        client. If the Auth service recognizes the token as valid, it
        responds with details describing the token and the client;
        otherwise, Auth's response simply indicates that the token was
        not found. After receiving Auth's response, the service can
        process the client's request or ask the client to retry with a
        valid token. </para>
    <para> You can see some OpenStack-oriented illustrations of these
        ideas, showing the OpenStack Keystone identity service
        authenticating for the OpenStack Nova compute service, at
            <link
            xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/trunk/openstack-identity/admin/content/example-flows.html"
            >http://docs.openstack.org/trunk/openstack-identity/admin/content/example-flows.html</link>.
        Some of the OpenStack functions illustrated may not be
        consistent with the privileges available to you as a Rackspace
        service administrator; you are very welcome to examine this
        and other OpenStack publications as general background
        material, but please rely on Rackspace sources for specific
        information about what you can do and how you can do
        it.</para>
    <para>
        If the service's authentication attempt fails, the authentication service returns <returnvalue>401</returnvalue> unAuth. 
    </para>
    <para>
        To use the Cloud Authentication Service effectively, you should understand several key concepts:
    </para>
    <xi:include href="identity-glossary.xml"/>
</chapter>