<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glossary [
<!-- changing authentication endpoints; define entities for US & UK rather than maintaining in text -->
<!ENTITY ENDPOINT-US "https://identity.api.rackspacecloud.com/v2.0/">
<!ENTITY ENDPOINT-UK "https://lon.identity.api.rackspacecloud.com/v2.0/">
]>
<glossary xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
    xml:id="Glossary-000">
        <title>Glossary</title>
        <glossentry xml:id="APIkey-d1e02">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">API Key</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> Your API Key is a unique alphanumeric
                    identifier associated with your account. You can
                    use your API key as an authentication credential,
                    paired with your username, to generate an
                    authentication <link linkend="Token-d1e13">token</link> which will be recognized by
                    the <link linkend="Service-d1e09">services</link>
                    in your <link linkend="Service_Catalog-d1e10">service catalog</link>. To find or generate your
                    API key, login to the Rackspace control
                    panel.</para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry> 
        <glossentry xml:id="Authentication-d1e01">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Authentication</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> 
                    Authentication is the act or process of confirming the identity of a
                    <link linkend="User-d1e15">user</link> or the truth of a claim. 
                    The authentication service confirms that an incoming request is being made by the user
                    who claims to be making the request.
                    It does this by validating a set of claims that the user makes.
                    These claims are initially in the form of a set of <link linkend="Credentials-d1e03">credentials</link>.
                    After initial confirmation based on credentials, 
                    the authentication service issues a <link linkend="Token-d1e13">token</link> to the user; 
                    when making subsequent requests,
                    the user can provide the token 
                    as evidence that the user's identity has already been authenticated.
                </para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry>  
        <glossentry xml:id="Credentials-d1e03">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Credentials</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> 
                    Credentials are data that belong to and identify a specific <link linkend="User-d1e15">user</link>.
                    Because credentials are assumed to be known by only one user, users who present valid
                    credentials are assumed to have proven that they are who they say they are.
                    Examples of credentials include:
                    <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
                        <listitem><para>a matching username and password</para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>a matching username and API key</para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>a unique token</para></listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry> 
        <glossentry xml:id="Endpoint-d1e05">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Endpoint</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> An endpoint is an entry point to an API. The
                    endpoint is defined as a set of base URLs. API
                    operations are defined relative to these URLs. An
                    API may offer several regional endpoints for a
                    single API. Rackspace provides two authentication
                    endpoints: one for US-based accounts and one for
                    UK-based accounts. To use v2.0 of the API for
                    authentication, specify the API version as shown
                    below: </para>
                <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
                    <listitem>
                        <para> US-based accounts authenticate through<?sbr?>
                        <link xlink:href="&ENDPOINT-US;">&ENDPOINT-US;</link>. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            UK-based accounts authenticate through <?sbr?>
                            <link xlink:href="&ENDPOINT-UK;">&ENDPOINT-UK;</link>.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    Your account may be based in either the US or the UK; this is not determined
                    by your physical location but by the location of the Rackspace retail site which
                    was used to create your account: 
                </para>
                <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            If your account was
                            created via <link xlink:href="http://www.rackspacecloud.com">http://www.rackspacecloud.com</link>, it is a US-based account.
                        </para>   
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            If your account was
                            created via <link xlink:href="http:/www.rackspace.co.uk">http:/www.rackspace.co.uk</link>, it is a UK-based account.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    If you are unsure how your account was created, use the Rackspace contact
                    information at either site to ask for help.
                </para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="Role-d1e07">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Role</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> 
                    A role is a personality that a <link linkend="User-d1e15">user</link> assumes when performing a specific set of operations.
                    A role includes a set of rights and privileges. 
                    A user assuming a role inherits
                    the rights and privileges associated with the role.
                    A <link linkend="Token-d1e13">token</link> that is issued to a user includes the list of roles the user 
                    can assume. When a user calls a <link linkend="Service-d1e09">service</link>, that service determines how to interpret a user's roles.
                    A role that grants access to a list of operations or resources within one service 
                    may grant access to a completely different list when interpreted by a different service.
                </para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry> 
        <glossentry xml:id="Service-d1e09">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Service</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> 
                    A service provides
                    one or more <link linkend="Endpoint-d1e05">endpoints</link> through which <link linkend="User-d1e15">users</link> 
                    can access resources and perform
                    operations.
                    Examples of OpenStack services include Compute (Nova), Object Storage (Swift), and Image Service (Glance). 
                </para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry> 
        <glossentry xml:id="Service_Catalog-d1e10">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Service Catalog</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> 
                    Your service catalog is the list of services available to you, as returned along with your authentication 
                    <link linkend="Token-d1e13">token</link> and an expiration date for that token.
                    All the services in your service catalog should recognize your token as valid until it expires.
                </para>
                <para>
                    The catalog listing for each service provides at least one endpoint URL for that service. 
                    Other information, such as regions and versions and tenants, is provided if it's relevant to your access to this service.
                </para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry> 
        <glossentry xml:id="Sub-User-d1e20">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Sub-User</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> A sub-user, also called a sub-account, is a
                child of the account's fully-privileged administrative
                user. Each account has exactly one administrative
                user, holding the <code>identity:user-admin</code>
                role; optionally, one or multiple sub-users can be
                created, each holding the
                    <code>identity:default</code> role. Each sub-user
                shares its parent's tenant information, group
                memberships, and endpoints. </para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="Tenant-d1e11">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Tenant</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> 
                    A tenant is a container used to group or isolate resources and/or identity
                    objects. Depending on the service operator, a tenant may map to a customer,
                    account, organization, or project.
                </para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry> 
        <glossentry xml:id="Token-d1e13">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Token</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef> 
                <para>
                    A token is an opaque string that represents an authorization to access cloud
                    resources. Tokens may be revoked at any time and are valid for a finite duration. 
                </para>
            </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
        <glossentry xml:id="User-d1e15">
            <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">User</emphasis></glossterm>
            <glossdef>
                <para> 
                    A user is a digital representation of a person, system, or service who consumes cloud services.
                    Users have credentials and may be assigned tokens; based on these credentials and tokens, 
                    the authentication service validates that incoming requests are being made by the user
                    who claims to be making the request, and that the user has the right to access the requested resources. 
                    Users may be directly assigned to a particular tenant and
                    behave as if they are contained within that tenant. 
                </para>
            </glossdef>    
        </glossentry> 
    </glossary>
