<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glossary [
<!-- changing authentication endpoints; define entities for US & UK rather than maintaining in text -->
<!ENTITY ENDPOINT-US "https://identity.api.rackspacecloud.com/v2.0/">
<!ENTITY ENDPOINT-UK "https://lon.identity.api.rackspacecloud.com/v2.0/">
<!ENTITY % common SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;
]>
<glossary xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="Glossary-000">
    <glossentry xml:id="Account-User-d1e20">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Account User</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para> An account user, which holds the <code>identity:default</code> role, is a child of exactly one
                fully-privileged account owner, which holds the <code>identity:user-admin</code>. An account owner can have
                many account users, which each share the account owner's tenant information, group memberships, and
                endpoints. </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    
    <glossentry xml:id="APIkey-d1e02">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">API Key</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>Your API Key is a unique alphanumeric identifier associated with your account. You can use your API key as
                an authentication credential, paired with your username, to generate an authentication
                <link linkend="Token-d1e13">token</link> which will be recognized by the
                <link linkend="Service-d1e09">services</link> in your
                <link linkend="Service_Catalog-d1e10">service catalog</link>. To find or generate your API key, login to the
                Rackspace Cloud Control Panel at
                <link xlink:href="http://mycloud.rackspace.com/">http://mycloud.rackspace.com/</link>.</para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Authentication-d1e01">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Authentication</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>The act of passing in <glossterm baseform="Credentials-d1e03">credentials</glossterm> confirming an identity, and returning a 
                token representation of the verified identity.</para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Authorization">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Authorization</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>Process that determines the capabilities available
                to an authenticated user, system or process.
                Authorization ensures that clients have appropriate
                access to information and information processing
                capabilities based on roles and policy-based access
                control defined by the organization.</para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    
    <glossentry xml:id="Credentials-d1e03">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Credentials</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>Credentials are data that belong to and identify a specific user. Because
                credentials are assumed to be known by only one user, users who present valid
                credentials are assumed to have proven that they are who they say they are. Examples
                of credentials include the following:<itemizedlist spacing="compact">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>a matching username and password</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>a matching username and API key</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>a unique token</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>secret question and answer</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>digital certificate</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>fingerprint</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="EndpointTemplate">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Endpoint Template</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>Endpoint templates provide Cloud Service providers with a method to define
                endpoints that apply to many or all tenants without having to create each endpoint
                on each tenant manually. For example, you can define an endpoint template and set
                the global attribute to true so that endpoint is automatically included in the
                Service catalog for all tenants authorized to use that service. For more
                information, see <olink targetdoc="Identity-Admin-Developer-Guide"
                    targetptr="Endpoint_Template_Calls">“Endpoint Templates”</olink>.</para>
        </glossdef>
      
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Endpoint-d1e05">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Endpoint</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para> An endpoint is an entry point to an API. The endpoint is defined as a set of base URLs. API operations are
                defined relative to these URLs. An API may offer several regional endpoints for a single API. Rackspace
                provides two authentication endpoints: one for US-based accounts and one for UK-based accounts. To use v2.0
                of the API for authentication, specify the API version as shown below: </para>
            <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
                <listitem>
                    <para> US-based accounts authenticate through<?sbr?>
                        <link xlink:href="&ENDPOINT-US;">&ENDPOINT-US;</link>. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para> UK-based accounts authenticate through <?sbr?>
                        <link xlink:href="&ENDPOINT-UK;">&ENDPOINT-UK;</link>. </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para> Your account may be based in either the US or the UK; this is not determined by your physical location but
                by the location of the Rackspace retail site which was used to create your account: </para>
            <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
                <listitem>
                    <para> If your account was created via
                        <link xlink:href="http://www.rackspacecloud.com">http://www.rackspacecloud.com</link>, it is a
                        US-based account. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para> If your account was created via
                        <link xlink:href="http://www.rackspace.co.uk">http://www.rackspace.co.uk</link>, it is a UK-based
                        account. </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para> If you are unsure how your account was created, use the Rackspace contact information at either site to
                ask for help. </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Role-d1e07">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Role</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>A role is a personality that a <glossterm xml:id="User-d1e15">user</glossterm> assumes when performing 
                a specific set of operations. A role includes a set of
                rights and privileges. A user assuming a role inherits the rights and privileges
                associated with the role. In &PRODNAME;, a <glossterm baseform ="Token-d1e13">token</glossterm> 
                that is issued to a user includes the list of roles the user can
                assume. When a user calls a <glossterm xml:id="Service-d1e09">service">service</glossterm>, the 
                service configuration determines how the user roles are interpreted  interpret a user's roles. A role that grants access to a
                list of operations or resources within one service can grant access to a completely
                different list when interpreted by a different service. </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Service">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Service</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para> A service provides one or more <link linkend="Endpoint-d1e05">endpoints</link> through which
                <glossterm xml:id="User-d1e15">users</glossterm> can access resources and perform operations. Examples of OpenStack
                services include Compute (Nova), Object Storage (Swift), and Image Service (Glance). </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Service_Catalog-d1e10">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Service Catalog</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para> Your service catalog is the list of services available to you, as returned along with your authentication
                <link linkend="Token-d1e13">token</link> and an expiration date for that token. All the services in your
                service catalog should recognize your token as valid until it expires. </para>
            <para> The catalog listing for each service provides at least one endpoint URL for that service. Other
                information, such as regions and versions and tenants, is provided if it's relevant to your access to this
                service. </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Account-User-d1e20">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Account User</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para> An account user, which holds the <code>identity:default</code> role, is a child of exactly one
                fully-privileged account owner, which holds the <code>identity:user-admin</code>. An account owner can have
                many account users, which each share the account owner's tenant information, group memberships, and
                endpoints. </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Service">
        <glossterm>Service</glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>Rackspace Cloud Identity Service allows you to define services, which are logical
                names for parts of Rackspace Cloud that provide internal or external capabilities,
                for things such as identity services, as well as compute and storage services. A
                service provides one or more endpoints through which users can access resources and
                perform operations. Examples of Rackspace Cloud services include Identity, Servers,
                Load Balancers, and Files.</para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
        
    <glossentry xml:id="Tenant-d1e11">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Tenant</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>A tenant is a container that can be used to group or isolate resources and
                identity objects. Depending on the service provider a tenant can map to a
                customer, account, organization, or project.</para>
            <para>In the &CLOUD;, tenants allow service providers to organize computing and
                storage resources without assigning them to user accounts directly. For example,
                Virtual machines (Cloud Servers) and containers (Cloud Files) are assigned to
                tenants, not to users directly.</para>
            <para>&CLOUD; has two tenant types: <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The Mosso tenant (Mosso account) ncludes the collection of
                        resources commonly associated with services such as Cloud Servers,
                        Cloud Database, Cloud Load Balancers.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Token-plain">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Token</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>A token is a temporary, encrypted form of identification that is passed to
                services as a proof of identity.</para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="Token-d1e13">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">Authentication token</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>An authenttication token is a string returned by &PRODNAME; in response to an
                authentication request submitted with valid credentials.</para>
            <para>Each authentication token has a scope that determines which services the client
                can access and an expiration that determines duration of access. In the &CIS;, 
                the default token expiration value is 24 hours. An Administrator or process can 
                revoke a token before its expiration if necessary.</para>
            <para>
                Each time you make an API request, you must include the authentication token and the API service endpoint. 
                When the authentication token expires, you must re-authenticate to the &CIS; to get a new token.
            </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry xml:id="User">
        <glossterm><emphasis role="bold">User</emphasis></glossterm>
        <glossdef>
            <para>A user is a digital representation of a person, system, or service that uses
                &CLOUD; services. Users have credentials and can be assigned tokens. They can
                present this information the &CIS; or other &CLOUD; services to confirm identity and 
                verify permission to access the requested system resources.
            </para>
            <para>
                Users can also be assigned to a tenant or region so that they inherit a set of 
                access rights and privileges automatically, based on the tenant or region configuration.
            </para>
        </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
</glossary>
