<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!-- changing authentication endpoints; define entities for US & UK rather than maintaining in text -->
<!ENTITY % common SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
]>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="Overview-d1e65">
    <title>Overview</title>
 <para>The Rackspace Cloud Identity service v2.0, an implementation of OpenStack Keystone Service
        v2.0, provides common, token-based authentication and authorization services that allow
        seamless access to Rackspace Cloud products and services.</para>
<para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Authentication generates a token in response to
                    valid credentials submitted by a user, process, or
                    client. Then, that token is used to confirm
                    identity when requesting access to systems or
                    resources defined in the Cloud Identity service
                    service catalog.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Authorization determines the resources and
                    actions available to a user, client, or process
                    based on access control capabilities that can be
                    defined and managed using the Rackspace Cloud
                    Identity service.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>Earlier versions of the Rackspace Identity service API, v1.0
        and v1.1 are known as the Rackspace Cloud Authentication
        service. These versions are not based on the OpenStack
        Keystone Identity service and only provide authentication
        services. </para>
    <para>Although each version of the API implements different
        features, you can use tokens generated from any API version to
        authenticate when making calls to Rackspace Cloud services.
        For example, if you use the v1.1 API to generate a token, you
        can use that token in calls to the v2.0 API. </para>
    <section xml:id="Intended_Audience-d1e73">
        <title>Intended Audience</title>
        <para condition="client">This Administration Guide is intended for Rackspace software developers interested in developing applications that use
            the Keystone Identity Admin API for authentication. The Rackspace Cloud Identity service, also known as the
            authentication service or "Auth", allows these developers to obtain an authentication token and a list of
            regional service endpoints to access available Rackspace services.</para>
        <para condition="admin">This Developer Guide is intended for software developers
            who want to use the Rackspace Cloud Identity service, an
            implementation of the OpenStack Keystone Identity service.
            Developers can learn how to develop applications that use
            the Identity service API for authentication,
            authorization, and service administration. </para>
        <para>To use this guide effectively, readers should be familiar with RESTful web services, HTTP/1.1,
            and JSON and/or XML serialization formats.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="Document_Change_History-d1e85">
        <title>Document Change History</title>
        <para>This version of the Developer Guide applies only to v2.0 of the API. The most recent changes are described in
            the table below:</para>
        <?rax revhistory?>
    </section> 
    <section xml:id="Additional_Resources-d1e130">
        <title>Additional Resources</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Read the <link xlink:href="http://docs.rackspace.com/">Rackspace API
                        Documentation</link> to learn about APIs for other Rackspace
                    services.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Visit the <link xlink:href="http://www.rackspace.com/knowledge_center/">Rackspace Knowledge Center</link> to 
                    learn how to use Rackspace services from the <link xlink:href="https://mycloud.rackspace.com/">Rackspace Cloud Control panel</link>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Find information about Rackspace SDKs and developer-focused articles and information on the 
                    <link xlink:href="https://developer.rackspace.com/">Rackspace Developer site</link>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Visit the <link xlink:href="https://feedback.rackspace.com">Rackspace Product Feedback forum</link> to share 
                    feedback and suggestions about Rackspace products and services, including this one.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Review the 
                    <link xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/keystone/">OpenStack Keystone documentation</link> to learn about 
                        the reference architecture for the Rackspace Cloud Identity service implementation.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <tip security="internal">
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">For Rackspace-internal use only:</emphasis> Check the Cloud
                Authentication and Identity wiki pages, beginning at <link
                    xlink:href="https://one.rackspace.com/display/auth/">Cloud Authentication and
                    Identity wiki</link>, for current operational information. The wiki also
                contains some step-by-step guidance on commonly-performed procedures. For example,
                the <link
                    xlink:href="https://one.rackspace.com/display/auth/Create+New+Admin+Users+in+Auth"
                    >Create New Service Users in Auth</link> page outlines creation of service users
                (identity:admin users) for Auth 1.1, and 2.0.</para>
        </tip>
    </section>
    <xi:include href="identity-endpoints.xml"/>
    <xi:include condition="admin" href="identity-releasenotes-v20-admin.xml"/>
    <xi:include condition="client" href="identity-releasenotes-v20-client.xml"/>

</chapter>
