<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section [
<!ENTITY % common SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;
]>
<section 
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
	xml:id="Sample_Catalog_Workflow-d1e266">
			<title>Suggested work flow for processing a Service Catalog response</title>
			<para>When your client issues a successful authentication request, the Cloud Identity Service
			returns a service catalog that shows the services available to that client, with one
			endpoint listed for each available service. (See <link xlink:href="Sample_Request_Response-d1e64.html">Annotated authentication request and response</link> 
				for a service catalog example.)</para>
			<para>As the client developer, you must decide how your client can use the contents of its
			service catalog. The first step is to identify a service that you want the client to
			access. Here is one possible work flow for processing the service catalog response to
			identify available services and their endpoints: </para>
			<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
					<para> 
						If the service catalog lists only one endpoint, use it.
						This endpoint connects your client to the only
						service available to that client.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> If the service catalog lists multiple endpoints, establish a process for the client to
					select the endpoint for the connection:  </para>
					<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
						<listitem>
							<para> If the user has not specified which endpoint to use,
								generate an error.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para> If the user has specified which endpoint to use, help
								the user identify that endpoint from
								within the catalog: </para>
							<orderedlist numeration="lowerroman">
								<listitem>
									<para>
										Support filtering by 
										endpoint name, service name, service type, region name, and version.
									</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>
										Support manual specification of an endpoint via a URL parameter. 
									</para>
								</listitem>
							</orderedlist>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<tip>
				<para>When you parse an authentication response programmatically, use the service <parameter>type</parameter> 
					instead of service <parameter>name</parameter> as the basis for determining whether a user has access
					to a particular kind of service. Service type is stable across all releases; new
					service types can be added, but existing service types are not renamed. If new compute services are added 
					with different names, the service <parameter>type</parameter> filter returns all available services.
					</para>
			</tip>
			<example><title>Connect a client to an endpoint listed as <code>type="compute"</code>.</title>
			
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Navigate to the endpoint for the specified compute, and use its <code>WWW-Authenticate</code>
							header to determine what authentication server it uses.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Go to that authentication server and authenticate.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Return to the compute endpoint and proceed with using the compute service.
						</para>
					
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</example>
		</section>