<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glossary [
<!ENTITY % common SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;
]>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="Identity-Concepts-e1362">
    <title>Identity concepts</title>
    <para>Before you begin using the  &CIS;, make sure you understand the following key
        concepts:</para>

    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term xml:id="User_concept">User</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>A user is a digital representation of a person, system, or service that uses
                    &CLOUD; services. Users have credentials and can be assigned tokens. Based on
                    these credentials and tokens,the authentication service validates that incoming
                    requests are being made by the user who claims to be making the request, and
                    that the user has the right to access the requested resources.</para>
                <para>In the &CLOUD; <glossterm xml:id="User-d1e1">Users</glossterm> are represented
                    as accounts created for specific individuals. When a user is created, the &CIS;
                    automatically assigns a user type and a default role based on the &CIS; system
                    configuration. Users with suffficient access rights and privileges can change
                    user role assighments if required.</para>
                <para>See the following links for more information: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem condition="client"><para><olink targetdoc="Identity-Developer-Guide"
                        targetptr="Account-Users-d1e910">"Identity users types and default
                        roles"</olink></para></listitem>
                        <listitem condition="client">
                            <para><olink targetdoc="Identity-Developer-Guide"
                                    targetptr="section_assign_roles_3">“Assigning Roles to Account
                                    Users”</olink></para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem condition="admin">
                            <para><olink targetdoc="Identity-Admin-Developer-Guide"
                                    targetptr="Account-Users-d1e910">“Identity user types and
                                    default roles”</olink></para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem condition="admin"><para><olink
                                targetdoc="Identity-Admin-Developer-Guide"
                                targetptr="section_assign_roles_3">“Assigning Roles to Account
                                    Users”</olink></para></listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Credentials</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>Any kind of information that can be used in verifying an identity. For the
                    &CIS;, credentials might include these types of information: <itemizedlist
                        spacing="compact">
                        <listitem>
                            <para>a matching username and password</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>a matching username and API key</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>a unique token issued to you</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>secret question and answer</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>verified cell phone number or email address</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Authentication</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>The act of passing in <glossterm baseform="Credentials-d1e03"
                        >credentials</glossterm>, confirming an identity, and returning a token
                    representation of the verified identity. In the &CLOUD;, credentials are
                    typically a username and API key.</para>
                <para>In the &CLOUD;, you authenticate by submitting a POST tokens API request with
                    valid credentials to the &CIS; endpoint. Credentials are typically a username
                    and API key. However, additional types of credentials can be accepted based on
                    service, tenant, or user account configuration.</para>
                <para>In response to valid credentials, the service returns an authentication token
                    and a service catalog with information about the &CLOUD; resources that you have
                    permission to access. You can use the authentication token and the service
                    endpoint to submit service requests through the &CIS; API or any other service
                    API that is included in the catalog. </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Authorization</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>The act of verifying the capability of an authenticated user, system, or
                    process to perform an action on a set of resources. In the &CLOUD;, the Identity
                    service provides centralized authorization to ensure that clients have
                    appropriate access to information and information processing capabilities based
                    on &CIS; roles such as system administrator and user administrator. The &CLOUD;,
                    also supports Role-based access control which defines product-specific roles to
                    authorize capabilities at the service-level.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Token</term>
            
            <listitem>
                <para>A token is a temporary, encrypted form of identification that is passed to
                services as a proof of identity.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Authentication token</term>
            <listitem><para>In the &CLOUD; an authenttication token is an encrypted string returned
                    by &PRODNAME; in response to an authentication request submitted with valid
                    credentials. The response also includes a service catalog with a list of &CLOUD;
                    services that can be accessed with the token.</para><para>To access a service,
                    include the authentication token in each request submitted to through the
                    service API. </para><para condition="client">Authentication tokens expire after
                    24 hours. To get a new token, users must submit another authentication request
                    to the &CIS;.</para>
                <para condition="admin">Authentication tokens expire after 24 hours. An
                    administrator or process can revoke a token before its expiration, if necessary. To
                    get a new token, you must submit another request to the &CIS;.</para></listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Tenant</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>A tenant is a container that can be used to group or isolate resources and
                    identity objects. Depending on the service provider a tenant can map to a
                    customer, account, organization, or project.</para>
                <para>In the &CLOUD;, tenants allow service providers to organize computing and
                    storage resources without assigning them to user accounts directly. For example,
                    Virtual machines (Cloud Servers) and containers (Cloud Files) are assigned to
                    tenants, not to users directly.</para>
                <para>&CLOUD; has two tenant types: <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>The Mosso tenant (Mosso account) ncludes the collection of
                                resources commonly associated withservices such as Cloud Servers,
                                Cloud Database, Cloud Load Balancers.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>The NAST tenant (NAST account) includes the collection of
                                resources commonly associated with Cloud Files and Cloud Files
                                CDN.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
                <para>Typically, a service provider determines how tenants are defined and used. The
                    &CIS; allows service administrators to create, delete, enable, and disable
                    tenants. Service administrators can also assign users and groups to one or more
                    tenants. Because each tenant can have its own role configuration, user might
                    have different roles, or different rights and privileges for the same role on
                    different tenants. </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry audience="client">
            <term>Service</term>
            <listitem>
                <para> A service is a logical name for the internal and external capailities
                    provided by a &CLOUD; platform or product component. A service provides one or
                    more endpoints through which <link linkend="User_concept">users</link> can access
                    resources and perform operations.</para>
                <para> In &CLOUD;, any system or product that can access the &CIS; API service such
                    as Cloud Servers, Cloud Load Balancers, and Cloud Files is considered a
                    service.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry audience="admin">
            <term>Service</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>&CIS; allows you to define services, which are logical names for parts of
                    &CLOUD; that provide internal or external capabilities, for things such as
                    identity services, as well as compute and storage services.</para>
                <para>A service provides one or more <link linkend="Endpoint-d1e05">endpoints</link>
                    through which <link linkend="User_concept">users</link> can access resources and
                    perform operations. Examples of &CLOUD; services include Identity, Servers, Load
                    Balancers, and Files.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry audience="client">
            <term xml:id="Endpoint-d1e05">Endpoint</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>A network accessible addresss, usually described by a URL, where a service can
                    be accessed.</para>
                <para>Various &CLOUD; systems query the &CIS; for the service endpoints required to
                    complete processes and operations. Users must know the URL for a service
                    endpoint in order to use the service.</para>
                <para> The &CIS; service endpoint, which is the entry point for the &CLOUD; can be
                    accessed from these endpoints: <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                <link xlink:href="&ENDPOINT-US;">&ENDPOINT-US;</link>
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><link xlink:href="&ENDPOINT-UK;">&ENDPOINT-UK;</link></para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
                <para> To get the URLs for other service endpoints, submit an authentication request
                    with valid credentials to a &CIS; endpoint. After successful authentication, the
                    &CIS; returns an authentication token and a service catalog with information
                    about available services, including the endpoints to access each service.<note>
                        <para>In &CIS; version 1.1, an endpoint was known as a baseURL.</para>
                    </note></para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry audience="admin">
            <term>Endpoint</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    A network accessible addresss, usually described by a URL, where a service can
                    be accessed.</para>
                <para>
                    Various &CLOUD; systems query the &CIS; for the service endpoints required to
                    complete processes and operations. Users must know the URL for a service
                    endpoint in order to use the service.</para>
                <para>
                    The &CIS; service endpoint, which is the entry point for the &CLOUD; can be
                    accessed from these endpoints: <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                <link xlink:href="&ENDPOINT-US;">&ENDPOINT-US;</link>
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                <link xlink:href="&ENDPOINT-UK;">&ENDPOINT-UK;</link>
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
                <para> To get the URLs for other service endpoints, submit an authentication request
                    with valid credentials to a &CIS; endpoint. After successful authentication, the
                    &CIS; returns an authentication token and a service catalog with information
                    about available services, including the endpoints to access each service.<note>
                        <para>In &CIS; version 1.1, an endpoint was known as a baseURL.</para>
                    </note></para>
                <para>Service developers can create and delete endpoints. They can also define
                    region-specific service endpoints for the same service API to customize service
                    availability and operation by region.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry audience="admin">
            <term>EndpointTemplate</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>Endpoint templates provide Cloud Service providers with a method to manage API
                    service endpoints that apply to many or all tenants without having to add each
                    endpoint on each tenant manually. </para>
                <para>For example, a Service developer can define a global endpoint template that
                    endpoint is automatically included in the Service catalog for all tenants
                    authorized to use that service. The endpoint template also specifies the URLs
                    for the internal, administrative, and public endpoints that provide access to
                    the service. </para>
                <para>See <olink targetdoc="Identity-Admin-Developer-Guide"
                        targetptr="Endpoint_Template_Calls">“Endpoint Templates”</olink> for
                    detailed information. </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Role</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>A role is a common security construct for assigning a specific set of access
                    rights and privileges to a user or group of users. Service administrators can
                    create named roles, configure the rights and privilieges for each role, and
                    manage the role without updating individual user or group accounts assigned to
                    the role.</para>
                <para>Roles can be assigned to users, groups, or tenants automatically based on
                    organization security policy. An administrator can view, manage, and update role
                    configuration and assignments as required. Only &CIS; service administrators can
                    create new roles.</para>
                <para>&CIS; supports two types of roles:<variablelist>
                        <varlistentry>
                            <term>Global roles</term>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>A global role defines access and permissions across all
                                    Rackspace systems, administrator or user-administrator, for
                                    example. Global roles are different than product roles as they
                                    indicate whether the user is acting as a service or as a
                                    customer.</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </varlistentry>
                        <varlistentry>
                            <term>Product roles</term>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                A product role defines the functions a user can perform for a
                                particular Rackspace cloud service.
                                </para>
                                </listitem>
                        </varlistentry>
                    </variablelist></para>
                <para>A user with a specific role inherits the rights and privileges associated with
                    the role. In &PRODNAME;, the authentication <glossterm baseform="Token-d1e13"
                        >token</glossterm> issued to a user includes the list of roles associated
                    with the user. When a user calls a <glossterm xml:id="Service-d1e09">service"
                        >service</glossterm>, the service configuration determines how the user
                    roles are interpreted. A role that grants access to certain resources or
                    capabilities within one service can grant access to completely different
                    resources and capabilities when interpreted by a different service.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Role-based access control (RBAC)</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>RBAC is method to restrict service access to only authorized users. RBAC
                    allows customers to specify who has access to resources and capabilities within
                    their cloud deployment, based on roles defined by Rackspace. For example, an
                    administrator can use RBAC to manage access to Cloud Servers as well as the
                    permissions to complete operations such as adding and deleting servers after
                    access has been granted.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    
</section>
