<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section [
<!ENTITY % common SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;
]>
<section 
	xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
	xmlns:xsdxt="http://docs.rackspacecloud.com/xsd-ext/v1.0"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" 
	xml:id="Service_Types-d1e265">
	<?dbhtml stop-chunking?>
	
	<title>Service types in the Service catalog</title>
		<para>Every service listed in the service catalog is associated with a service type. You can use
		the service type to recognize services that perform similar functions, whatever those
		services are named. The following table shows all the available service types and provides
		information about any related OpenStack services. To learn more about any of the Rackspace
		services listed, see the <link xlink:href="http://docs.rackspace.com/api/">Rackspace
			developer documentation.</link></para>
		<table rules="all" width="80%">
		<caption>Service Types</caption>
		<col width="40%"/>
		<col width="60%"/>
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th>Service Type</th>
				<th>Description</th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody>
			<tr>
				<td><code>compute</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type provide managed VMs and bare-metal servers in the
						cloud. </para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Servers</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace service of
						this type. This Rackspace service is compatible with the OpenStack Compute
						(Nova) API 1.1 as documented at <link
							xlink:href="http://nova.openstack.org/"
							>http://nova.openstack.org/</link>. </para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>identity</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type provide authentication, authorization, administration, and audit
						capabilities to provision and manage users that request access to Rackspace
						Cloud service endpoints.  </para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Identity</emphasis> is the name of the Rackspace service of
						this type. The Rackspace service is compatible with OpenStack Keystone API
						2.0 as documented at <link xlink:href="http://keystone.openstack.org/"
							>http://keystone.openstack.org/</link>. </para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>image</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type offer retrieval, storage, and metadata assignment for Rackspace
						Cloud Server images. </para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Images</emphasis> is the name of the Rackspace service of
						this type. The Rackspace service is compatible with the OpenStack Glance API
						as documented at <link xlink:href="http://glance.openstack.org/"
							>http://glance.openstack.org/</link>. </para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>object-store</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type provide scalable cloud object storage for files and
						media. </para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Files</emphasis> is the name of the Rackspace service of
						this type. The Rackspace service is compatible with the OpenStack Swift API
						as documented at <link xlink:href="http://swift.openstack.org/"
							>http://swift.openstack.org/</link>. </para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>network</code></td>
				<td><para>Services of this type enable you to create isolated networks that provision
					server instances with Rackspace networks or the isolated networks you
					create.</para>
					<para>Rackspace supports two services of this type: <emphasis role="italic">Cloud
							Networks</emphasis>, which is compatible with the <link
							xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/api/openstack-network/2.0/content/index.html"
							>OpenStack Networking service</link> and the <emphasis role="italic"
							>nova-network</emphasis> component of the <emphasis role="italic"
							>Rackspace Cloud Servers</emphasis> API, which is compatible with the
						network component of the <link
							xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/nova/devref/index.html"
							>OpenStack Nova API.</link>
					</para></td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>volume</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type provide online object storage for files and allow
						customers to mount drives or volumes to their Rackspace Next Generation
						Cloud Servers™. </para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud BlockStorage</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace service
						of this type. The Rackspace service is built on the <link
							xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/api/openstack-block-storage/1.0/content/"
							>OpenStack Cinder project</link>.</para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:autoscale</code></td>
				<td><para>Services of this type enable you to define policies to dynamically scale cloud resources in
					response to changing workloads.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Auto Scale</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace service of this
						type.</para></td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:backup</code></td>
				<td><para>Services of this type enable you to create and manage backup versions of cloud server files
						and folders that you select, and to restore files to their original location
						or to another server.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Backup</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace service of
						this type.</para></td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:bigdata</code></td>
				<td><para>Services of this type provide on-demand Apache Hadoop service available in the Rackspace Cloud
						that enable you to deploy, manage, and scale Hadoop clusters.</para>
						<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud BigData</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace service of
						this type.</para></td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:database</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type provide fast, scalable, fully managed MySQL
						databases in the Rackspace Cloud.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Databases</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace service of
						this type. </para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:dns</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type simplify and automate DNS management.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud DNS</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace service of this
						type. </para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:feeds</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services if this type enable customers on the Rackspace public cloud to access and
						collect near real-time usage and system event data that can be used for
						analysis, monitoring, and automation.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Feeds</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace service of this
						type.</para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:load-balancer</code></td>
				<td><para>Services of this type provide on-demand, scalable traffic management.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Load Balancers</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace Cloud service of this type.
					</para></td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:cloudmetrics</code></td>
				<td><para>Services of this type allow users to collect and analyze various metrics  and to quickly
						iterate through the data with queries and set up dashboard metrics for
						ongoing metrics monitoring.</para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Metrics</emphasis> is the name of a
						Rackspace service of this type.</para></td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:monitor</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type enable you to create custom infrastructure monitoring with
						real-time alerts, always-on notifcations, and flexible configurations. </para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Monitoring</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace service of
						this type. </para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr condition="admin">
				<td><code>rax:object-cdn</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type enable you to distribute content globally in order to optimize
						response times for users accessing web page and media content. </para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Content Delivery Network (CDN)</emphasis> is the
						name of a Rackspace service of this type.</para>
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:orchestration</code></td>
				<td><para>Services of this type enable you to automate and standardize cloud infrastructure
					setup and management.</para>
					<para>Cloud Orchestration is the name of the Rackspace service of this type. The Rackspace
						service is compatible with the <link
							xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/heat/">OpenStack Heat
							API</link>.</para></td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td><code>rax:queues</code></td>
				<td>
					<para>Services of this type  provide an open source, scalable, and highly
						available message and notifications service.  </para>
					<para><emphasis role="italic">Cloud Queues</emphasis> is the name of a Rackspace
						service of this type.</para>
				</td>
			</tr>
		</tbody>
	</table>
</section>
