<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glossary [
<!ENTITY % common SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;
]>
<section 
	xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
	xmlns:xsdxt="http://docs.rackspacecloud.com/xsd-ext/v1.0"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
	xml:id="RBAC-roles" xreflabel="RBAC roles">
	<?dbhtml stop-chunking?>
	
	<title>RBAC roles</title>
	<para> RBAC roles are cusotmer-managed roles with specific
		permissions that determine the services a user can access and
		the types of operations they can complete. For example, an
		account user with the <literal>lbaas:admin</literal> role has create, read, 
		update, and delete permissions for the Cloud Loadbalancer service.
		</para>
	<para>All RBAC roles are subordinate to the 
			<literal>identity:user-admin</literal> or  the
			<literal>identity:user-manage</literal> roles that the Identity 
		service assigns to Rackspace Cloud accounts held by the account owner or by 
		an account designated to manage user accounts. Only Identity administrators 
		and managers can create account users (<literal>identity:default</literal>) and assign RBAC
		roles. Account owners cannot hold any additional roles because
		they already have full access to all services and
		capabilities. Account managers can have both the <parameter>identity:user-manage</parameter> and the 
		<parameter>identity:default</parameter>.</para>
	<para>Role assignments can be global or custom. Global roles manage
		access and permissions across multiple API services. Custom
		roles manage access and permissions on a per-product basis.
		For both global and custom roles, the user has access only to
		designated products. <xref linkend="RBAC_roledesc_table"/>
		describes the RBAC roles available.</para>
	<table rules="all" width="100%" xml:id="RBAC_roledesc_table">
		<caption>Rackspace Cloud RBAC Roles and Capabilities</caption>
		<thead>
			<tr>
				<th>Role</th>
				<th>Type</th>
				<th>Role Description</th>
				<th>Example Role</th>
			</tr>
		</thead>
		<tbody>
			<tr>
				<td>admin (full access)</td>
				<td>Global</td>
				<td>The admin role provides Create, Read, Update, and Delete
					permissions in all Cloud products, where access is
					granted. Full access is given to current and
					future products as they become RBAC-enabled. Each
					account can have only one admin user.</td>
				<td>admin</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>observer (read-only access)</td>
				<td>Global</td>
				<td>The observer role provides Read permission in all products where
					access is granted. Read-only access is given to current and future
					products as they become RBAC-enabled.</td>
				<td>observer</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>product:admin</td>
				<td>Custom</td>
				<td>The product:admin role provides Create, Read, Update, and Delete
					permissions for a specified product, where access is granted.</td>
				<td>nova:admin</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>product:creator</td>
				<td>Custom</td>
				<td>The product:creator role provides Create, Read, and Update
					permissions for a specified product, where access is granted. The
					user cannot delete resources.</td>
				<td>cloudFiles:creator</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>product:observer</td>
				<td>Custom</td>
				<td>This product:observer role provides Read permission for a specified
					product, where access is granted.</td>
				<td>cdb:observer</td>
			</tr>
		</tbody>
	</table>
</section>
